# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello, everyone. I'm Wang Gang.
# 本期视频我跟大家分享一道家常菜
In this video I'm going to share a homestyle dish with you.
# 藕片蒸肉
Steamed sliced lotus root with pork
# 首先我们准备莲藕1小节
First let's prepare a small lotus root.
# 切掉头尾之后去皮备用
Cut off the head and tail of the root and peel the skin.
# 然后将莲藕直接切成一连刀片备用
Then cut the lotus root into "pocket" slice. (Two thin slices attached in the middle)
# 同学们切记不能切太厚
Don't cut too thick.
# 最好保持2毫米左右
It's best to keep it about 2mm.
# 切好之后放入清水中清洗浸泡备用
After cutting, rinse and soak in water.
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Start preparing other ingredients next.
# 准备五花肉1小块切成片之后剁碎备用
Prepare 1 small piece of pork belly, cut into slices and chop into mince.
# 不喜欢肥肉的同学也可以选择里脊肉或者前腿肉
Those who don't like fatty meat can also use tenderloin or leg meat.
# 下一步开始准备素菜
Next, preparing the other veggies.
# 将莲藕的两头去皮之后剁碎备用
Chop some of the peeled lotus root into small pieces.
# 再准备适量的胡萝卜和香菇一起剁碎备用
Also prepare some carrots and shiitake mushrooms and chop them into small pieces.
# 最后准备适量的姜葱切碎之后加入肉末中备用
Finally, chop some ginger and scallions and add it to the pork mince.
# 下一步开始腌制
Next, start marinating.
# 盆中加入适量的食用盐（约0.5克）
Add a bit table salt to the pork (about 0.5 grams)
# 加入适量的酱油（约3克）
Add some light soy sauce (about 3 grams)
# 加入蚝油3克
Add 3 grams of oyster sauce
# 加入黄酒20克
Add 20g of huangjiu rice wine
# 再加入适量的老抽之后搅拌均匀
Then add a bit of dark soy sauce and mix well.
# 搅拌均匀之后再加入1小把现磨米粉
Mix well then add 1 small handful of freshly ground rice flour.
# 加米粉的目的是增加肉末的口感
The purpose of adding rice flour is to add texture to the mince.
# 米粉也可以选择制作粉蒸肉的袋装米粉（超市有售）
Or you can use pre-packaged rice flour (available in supermarkets)
# 再加入1小把干淀粉将水份收干
Add another handful of dry starch to absorb the liquid.
# 最后再加入切好的辅料搅拌均匀即可
Finally, add the chopped ingredients and mix well.
# 下一步开始装肉
Next, start loading the meat.
# 将拌好的肉末放入切好的莲藕夹片中
Place the mixture into the sliced lotus root "pocket".
# 然后均匀地摆放整齐即可
Then just arrange them evenly and neatly.
# 下一步开始调汁
Next, let's season the sauce.
# 盆中加入适量的酱油和蚝油
Add some light soy sauce and oyster sauce to a bowl
# 再加入几勺白糖搅拌均匀即可
Add a few tablespoons of sugar and mix well
# 此菜口味为咸鲜回甜
This dish is savory and sweet.
# 当然也可以按照各自的口味调料汁
Of course, you can also make your own sauce to suit your taste.
# 然后将莲藕放入蒸锅中开中火蒸12分钟即可
Then place the lotus root in a steamer and steam on medium heat for 12 minutes.
# 12分钟之后取出莲藕片
Take the lotus root out after 12 minutes.
# 下一步开始准备勾芡淋汁
The next step is to prepare the sauce.
# 锅中直接加入调好的料汁
Add the sauce directly to the wok.
# 再加入适量的蜂蜜水烧开
Then add some honey water and bring it to boil
# 烧开之后加入适量的水淀粉把料汁收紧
After boiling, add some slurry to thicken the sauce.
# 最后再均匀地淋在藕片上面即可上菜
Finally pour the sauce evenly over the lotus root slices and serve.
# 一道非常美味的藕片蒸肉末就制作完成
A very tasty steamed sliced lotus root with pork is ready!
# 下面开始技术总结
Let's start the technical summary.
# 第一 莲藕最好切成比较薄的连刀片这样口感会更脆
Firstly, the lotus root should be cut into thin slices with one end attached for the best crunchy texture.
# 第二 夹心的肉可以选择猪肉
Second, the meat used for the filling can be pork.
# 也可以选择牛肉
Or you can also use beef.
# 肥瘦都可以根据个人口味添加
You can adjust the ratio of fatty to lean meat to suit your own taste.
# 第三 没有米粉的同学也可以加入适量的米饭代替米粉
Thirdly, if you don't have rice flour, you can also add some rice instead of rice flour.
# 这样的口感也比较有清晰的层次感
This also gives it a bit more texture.
# 藕片蒸肉末的技术总结完毕
End of technique summary for steamed sliced lotus root with pork